<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><kml xmlns="http://earth.google.com/kml/2.1">
<!-- 
cached data at 10:54:15
cached id b8984d54b98368259362065ad1cf545b
-->
<Document><description>Latest incident updates nationally</description><StyleMap id="m_ylw-pushpin_copy1"><Pair><key>normal</key><styleUrl>#s_ylw-pushpin</styleUrl></Pair><Pair><key>highlight</key><styleUrl>#s_ylw-pushpin_hl</styleUrl></Pair></StyleMap><Style id="s_ylw-pushpin"><IconStyle><scale>1.2</scale><Icon><href>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/images/maps/helmet01.png</href></Icon><hotSpot x="0.5" y="0" xunits="fraction" yunits="fraction"/></IconStyle><LabelStyle><color>ffffffcc</color><scale>0</scale></LabelStyle><BalloonStyle><text>&lt;strong&gt;$[name]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$[description]</text><textColor>ff000000</textColor><color>00ffffff</color><displayMode>default</displayMode><scale>1</scale></BalloonStyle></Style><Style id="s_ylw-pushpin_hl"><IconStyle><scale>1.2</scale><Icon><href>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/images/maps/helmet01.png</href></Icon><hotSpot x="0.5" y="0" xunits="fraction" yunits="fraction"/></IconStyle><LabelStyle><color>ffffffcc</color><scale>0</scale></LabelStyle><BalloonStyle><text>&lt;strong&gt;$[name]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;$[description]</text><textColor>ff000000</textColor><color>00ffffff</color><displayMode>default</displayMode><scale>1</scale></BalloonStyle></Style><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Hermits Peak Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-105.399</longitude><latitude>35.718</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Hermits Peak Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Mon, 18 Apr 2022 10:35:26</p><p>Incident is 61% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>  </p><p>The Las Dispensas prescribed fire on the Pecos/Las Vegas Ranger District of the Santa Fe National Forest was declared a wildfire at approximately 4:30 p.m. on April 6, 2022. Although forecasted weather conditions were within parameters for the prescribed fire, unexpected erratic winds in the late afternoon caused multiple spot fires that spread outside the project boundary. Named the Hermits Peak Fire, the wildfire is approximately 12 miles northwest of Las Vegas, NM at the base of Hermits Peak in the Pecos Wilderness. The Hermits Peak Fire is burning through mixed conifer in steep, rugged terrain that poses challenges for firefighter access.  </p>   <p>  </p>   <p>The Southwest Area Type 1 Incident Management Team 1, led by Incident Commander Carl Schwope, assumed command of the Hermits Peak Fire at 7:00 AM on Thursday, April 15, 2022. The Type 1 Incident Management Team brings additional resources and management capabilities to implement a full suppression strategy for the Hermits Peak Fire. </p>  ]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8049/">View Hermits Peak Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-105.399</longitude><latitude>35.718</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-105.399,35.718,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Nogal Canyon Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-105.747</longitude><latitude>33.511</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Nogal Canyon Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Sun, 17 Apr 2022 21:09:58</p><p>Incident is 58% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>Jurisdiction: State and Lincoln National ForestContainment: 4%Size: 433 acresEvacuations: All of Nogal CanyonCause: Downed Power LinesDate/Time Detected: April 12, 2022, 1:25pmLocation: Nogal Canyon and Pennsylvania CanyonFirefighting Resources: County and Forest Service firefighers. Fuel Type: Grasses, brush, timberStructures Lost: 6 Primary Residences, 8 OutbuildingsValues at Risk: Homes and outbuildingsFire Update: 6 Primary structures and 8 outbuildings have been lost on the Nogal Canyon Fire, that started on April 12, 2022. Nogal Canyon remains under immediate evacuation notice. Firefighters continue to do point protection around homes and structures. </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8062/">View Nogal Canyon Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-105.747</longitude><latitude>33.511</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-105.747,33.511,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>McBride Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-105.635</longitude><latitude>33.333</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>McBride Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Sun, 17 Apr 2022 21:10:45</p><p>Incident is 80% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>The McBride Fire started on April 12, 2022 around 2:30 pm on Warrior Rd in Ruidoso, NM. The fire quickly spread into neighboring residential areas and has continued to move northeast towards the airport. There are 2 confirmed fatalities and over 200 homes have been lost. </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8061/">View McBride Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-105.635</longitude><latitude>33.333</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-105.635,33.333,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Nina Lucia Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-100.567</longitude><latitude>32.175</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Nina Lucia Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Mon, 18 Apr 2022 09:13:28</p><p>Incident is 25% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p> The Nina Lucia Fire started along County Road 273 approximately 6 miles southwest of the town of Maryneal. Texas A&M Forest Service (TAMFS) was requested and is working in unified command with local responders. Heavy equipment was engaged on the ground to begin working the flanks of the fire while aviation resource made several drops to try and slow forward progression. Currently the Nina Lucia Fire is burning in heavy Brush and grass with a moderate rate of spread.</p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8065/">View Nina Lucia Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-100.567</longitude><latitude>32.175</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-100.567,32.175,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Big Hole Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-106.747</longitude><latitude>34.665</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Big Hole Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Sun, 17 Apr 2022 09:30:21</p><p>Incident is 80% contained.</p><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8059/">View Big Hole Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-106.747</longitude><latitude>34.665</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-106.747,34.665,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Mesa Re-Entry Rx Fire Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-109.434</longitude><latitude>33.317</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Mesa Re-Entry Rx Fire Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Fri, 15 Apr 2022 10:46:46</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>The Clifton Ranger District on the Apache-Sitgreaves National Forests is planning to proceed with the Mesa Re-Entry prescribed burn project beginning as soon as Monday, April 18th and activity could extend through the end of the month as conditions allow. <p>The Mesa Re-Entry prescribed burn project is spread across approximately 8,000 acres, and smoke will be expected to be seen through the month of April, depending on weather conditions. The project area is bounded to the north and west by Pine Flat Road (FR 515), to the south by Upper Eagle Creek Road (FR 217), and to the east by sections of Corral Creek and Sheep Wash Canyon.</p> <p>Public safety notices will be posted in the vicinity of the project, and travelers should use caution when in the area. Fire planners expect to take advantage of forecasted cool temperatures and lower winds in the coming days, and the project area will include a comprehensive safety strategy including control features and pretreating vulnerable areas.</p> <p>Prescribed fires like the Mesa Re-Entry project are part of the <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/managing-land/wildfire-crisis">Forest Service’s comprehensive 10-year strategy</a> for protecting communities and improving resilience in America’s forests. The intent of the Wildfire Management Strategy is to increase fuels treatments that help firefighters respond safely to incidents, restore and maintain resilient landscapes, and create fire-adapted communities. The plan calls for treating up to an additional 20 million acres of National Forest System lands, and up to an additional 30 million acres of other federal, state, tribal and private lands.</p> <p>Smoke is expected to be visible along Highway 191, Morenci and the community of Eagle Creek but is not expected to impact travel. Smoke-sensitive individuals and people with respiratory or heart disease are encouraged to take precautionary measures. Information on air quality and active prescribed burns can be found on Arizona Department of Environmental Quality’s webpage: <a href="https://azdeq.gov/">https://azdeq.gov/</a>.</p> <p>The public can obtain additional information by calling the Clifton Ranger District at (928) 687-8600.</p> <p>Stay up to date on news from the A - S at our website <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/asnf">https://www.fs.usda.gov/asnf</a>, on <a href="https://twitter.com/A_SNFs">Twitter</a> @A_SNFs and on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/apachesitgreavesnfs">facebook.com/apachesitgreavesnfs</a>.</p></p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8064/">View Mesa Re-Entry Rx Fire Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-109.434</longitude><latitude>33.317</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-109.434,33.317,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>GWJ National Forest Prescribed Burns Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-79.861</longitude><latitude>37.671</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>GWJ National Forest Prescribed Burns Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Mon, 14 Feb 2022 13:03:08</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>The George Washington and Jefferson National Forests will conduct prescribed burns in multiple counties this spring. Prescribed burns improve wildlife habitat by restoring open woodlands and grasslands to the forest landscape. Safety is the Forest Service’s top priority, and Forest fire managers will conduct prescribed burns only under appropriate weather conditions. Experienced fire managers will closely monitor local weather conditions, such as wind and humidity, and adjust the schedule as needed to ensure the safety of both crewmembers and local residents. Prior to lighting the burn, crews construct and designate firebreaks to ensure the fire does not leave the burn area. The burn will mimic historic natural fire as much as possible. Some individual trees will burn, but the fire should travel mostly across the forest floor. For thousands of years, fire shaped our forests and wildlife and our lands need fire to be healthy. Low intensity prescribed burns create open areas where a diverse mix of grasses, plants and wildflowers grow, and provide valuable food and cover for wildlife such as bear, deer, turkey and migratory birds. The Forest Service works closely with partners and is able to accomplish this important habitat work thanks to help from The Nature Conservancy, the Virginia Department of Wildlife Resources and the Virginia Department of Forestry, among others. </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7945/">View GWJ National Forest Prescribed Burns Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-79.861</longitude><latitude>37.671</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-79.861,37.671,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Side Oats Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-101.903</longitude><latitude>33.133</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Side Oats Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Wed, 13 Apr 2022 20:56:50</p><p>Incident is 100% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>The Side Oats fire started on April 13, 2022 at approximately 2:15 pm in Lynn CountyThe Texas A&M Forest Service is in unified command with the local VFD's </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8063/">View Side Oats Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-101.903</longitude><latitude>33.133</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-101.903,33.133,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Animas City Mountain Prescribed Burn Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-107.872</longitude><latitude>37.323</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Animas City Mountain Prescribed Burn Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Sun, 18 Jul 2021 17:48:57</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p> In order to reduce the risk of high-intensity wildfire, improve forest health and wildlife habitat, the Bureau of Land Management Tres Rios Field Office has planned a prescribed fire treatment for up to 652 acres on Animas City Mountain in Durango, Colorado. Dependent on weather and the availability of firefighters to conduct the operation, the prescribed burns could take place in the spring of 2022. An Environmental Assessment which covers this, as well as other treatment areas in La Plata County, has been completed and is available here: <a href="https://eplanning.blm.gov/eplanning-ui/project/1505044/510" target="_self">Final Environmental Assessment</a>.</p> <p>Prescribed fires require a comprehensive plan consisting of 21 elements. The plan outlines the methodical process from inception to completion. The Animas City Mountain project is expected to take 2-3 days for ignitions, with additional time to patrol the area and extinguish hot spots. The mountain has been divided into seven units or compartments. Crews are expected to begin burning on the top of the mountain by slowly lighting an edge that has already been thinned with chainsaws. Once a secure edge or “black line” has been established, firefighters ignite the interior of each unit, one unit at a time. The fire then burns back toward the secured, black edge. This methodical approach allows firefighters opportunities to halt ignitions if burning conditions become undesirable. Examples of undesirable conditions are fire behavior that is too active/not active enough, and poor smoke dispersion. Firefighters will also have water on hand to cool things down if fire activity grows beyond a desirable level.  </p> <p>   </p> <p>Prescribed fires are watched carefully by firefighters around the burn, lookouts at more distant locations, aerially (helicopters, planes, drones), and with calibrated smoke monitors. These monitors will be placed at locations around the burn to track smoke impacts in real time. The BLM and Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment Air Quality (CPDHE) have been working since 2018 to develop a permit that accomplishes the burn while minimizing smoke impacts to the surrounding area. Prescribed fire smoke may affect your health. For more information, visit <a data-auth="NotApplicable" data-linkindex="0" href="https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/cdphe/wood-smoke-and-health" target="_blank">https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/cdphe/wood-smoke-and-health</a>. Prescribed fires are a tool to minimize smoke impacts to communities by careful selection of when fires burn and when they stop. Firefighters utilize compartments to halt the fire from spreading overnight, whereas wildfire continue to burn overnight when smoke is likely to settle into low lying areas where communities are located. Residual smoke from the interior areas of the compartments is anticipated, but the goal is to start early in the day and stop early in the evening to give material as much time as possible to be consumed before night-time cooling occurs and smoke sinks into the valley.  </p> <p> Ideal timing (windows) for the project occurs during the Spring and Fall when conditions are more favorable for low-intensity fire. Fuel (vegetation) and weather conditions must fall within a predetermined “prescription” that is known to yield desirable results while still being controllable by the fire personnel conducting the burn. Dissipation of smoke is also part of the prescription. Prescription development has been done by local fire experts who utilize fire behavior computer modeling software combined with decades of experience conducting prescribed burn in southwest Colorado. </p> <p> This project is a coordinated effort between the federal/county/local government, NGOs, emergency managers, fire departments, public health officials, state smoke regulators and nearby residents. The burn is planned to take place over the course of 2-3 days. Brief closure of Animas City Mountain during the ignitions will occur for public and firefighter safety. The containment lines used for the project will consist of BLM designated trails. The units will be ignited using a combination of ground and aerial resources and will be patrolled/mopped up until out. </p> <p> The project is part of the BLM’s ongoing commitment to protecting human health and safety while maintaining or enhancing forest and woodland health and functionality. The Animas City Mountain area was previously masticated in 2010 which altered the vertical structure of the forest stand to reduce the risk of catastrophic fire. Mastication is a treatment method where the understory is mowed and mulched with a large machine. The mulched material slowly decomposes, while the understory regrows. Mastication and prescribed fire are effective in preventing fires from leaving the ground and becoming “crown” fires where the entire trees or stand of trees burn. Treatments thin and remove some of the large dense understory or “ladder fuels”. </p> <p> Vegetation, however, grows back and requires maintenance. Prescribed fire is the best treatment option for this forest type, if possible, after the initial mechanical treatment. While consuming some of the standing vegetation; prescribed fire also eliminates material left on the ground from both mastication and the natural shedding of leaves, needles, etc. Fire is the only natural process used as a treatment method and produces the most effective results for hazardous fuel reduction while enhancing woodland health. Ponderosa pine woodlands are a drought resistant species that have evolved with a natural cycle of frequent, low-intensity fire. </p> <p> Prescribed fire mimics this natural process and improves forage for wildlife, as well as increasing plant diversity by creating breaks in the understory where grasses and flowers can thrive. </p> <p> Every year the west is impacted by large catastrophic wildfires. Prescribed fires and other treatment methods lessen the impacts of future fires and increase the likelihood firefighters can work safely and be effective at stopping fires in and near treated areas. </p> <p></p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7688/">View Animas City Mountain Prescribed Burn Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-107.872</longitude><latitude>37.323</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-107.872,37.323,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Research Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-101.997</longitude><latitude>33.64</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Research Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Wed, 13 Apr 2022 13:32:44</p><p>Incident is 100% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>Research Fire started on April 12, 2022 at approximately 2:00 pm.Texas A&M Forest Service is in unified command with the local VFD's </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8060/">View Research Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-101.997</longitude><latitude>33.64</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-101.997,33.64,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Overflow Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-104.363</longitude><latitude>33.269</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Overflow Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Wed, 13 Apr 2022 11:10:22</p><p>Incident is 100% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>On April 7, 2022, the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) declared the Overflow Prescribed Fire to be a wildfire when an unexpected fire whirl carried fire across the control lines. The fire is located southeast of Roswell, along the Pecos River corridor, in Chaves County.Prescribed fire ignitions began at 11:35 a.m., within pre-determined parameters, called a prescription. The fire whirl, a dust-devil-like phenomenon, changed the fire intensity along control lines and spread the fire across the boundary. A fire whirl is a vortex-induced by extreme heat in the fire environment and is often composed of flame, debris, and ash and can travel distances similar to tornadoes. Fuels in the area are dry grasses and salt cedar. Upon the breach of the control lines, the BLM declared the event an escaped prescribed fire, which converted to a wildfire, at 1:25 p.m. <p style="overflow-wrap: break-word; margin-top: 0px; margin-bottom: 15px; padding: 0px; border: 0px; outline: 0px; font-size: 14px; vertical-align: baseline; background: 0px 0px rgb(254, 254, 254); color: rgb(51, 51, 51); font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;">The following cooperating agencies have contributed resources to the containment of the Overflow Fire: Chaves County, Carlsbad and Ruidoso Fire Departments, New Mexico Forestry, U.S. Forest Service, and U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service. Presently, there are six engines and two hot-shot crews on site.  </p>Smoke from the Overflow Fire may be visible to residents and visitors. Smoke-sensitive individuals and people with respiratory problems or heart disease are encouraged to take precautionary measures. The New Mexico Department of Health (NMDOH) Environmental Public Health Tracking (EPHT) website can provide air quality information and protect your health.  </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8053/">View Overflow Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-104.363</longitude><latitude>33.269</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-104.363,33.269,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Burke Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-95.527</longitude><latitude>31.404</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Burke Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Mon, 11 Apr 2022 19:19:13</p><p>Incident is 100% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p> On Monday, April 11th, Texas A&M Forest Service was requested to assist with a wildfire in a pine plantation located approximately three miles northwest of Crockett, TX between Highway 287 and 229. Crews arrived on scene at approximately 9:00 am and found the fire to be approximately 200 acres with low fire behavior, and not threatening any homes or structures. The fire is believed to have been burning for at least two days prior to the request call, and the cause of ignition is currently under investigation. </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8058/">View Burke Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-95.527</longitude><latitude>31.404</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-95.527,31.404,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Southwest District BLM Prescribed Fire  Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-108.826</longitude><latitude>37.903</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Southwest District BLM Prescribed Fire  Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Thu, 23 Sep 2021 13:00:52</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>The Bureau of Land Management Southwest District plans to conduct several prescribed burns beginning early October or as conditions allow. The prescribed burn projects will be on the Gunnison, Tres Rios and Uncompahgre Field Offices. The planned burns are part of larger projects to reduce hazardous fuels; protect wildland-urban interface communities; improve big game habitat, sage grouse habitat, and range conditions; and reintroduce fire to a fire-adapted ecosystem to restore healthy forests and species diversity.  While no road closures are expected during the projects, camping near the units is discouraged due to increased traffic and likelihood of smoke in the area, particularly at night. Multiple days of burning may occur throughout the fall into the winter, as fuel conditions and weather permit. Project areas will be monitored once completed to ensure public safety. While smoke may be visible in the burn area at times, most of the smoke will lift and dissipate during the warmest parts of the day. Expect visible smoke in the area for several days after each burn is completed as vegetation in the interior continues to smolder. The BLM obtained smoke permits from the Colorado State Air Pollution Control Division, which identify atmospheric conditions under which the burns can be implemented. Prescribed fire smoke may affect your health. For more information, visit <a href="https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/cdphe/wood-smoke-and-health">https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/cdphe/wood-smoke-and-health</a>.</p><p>Specific information on upcoming prescribed burn projects can be found in the News section.</p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7852/">View Southwest District BLM Prescribed Fire  Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-108.826</longitude><latitude>37.903</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-108.826,37.903,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Bitterroot Spring RX Fire 2022 Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-114.176</longitude><latitude>46.081</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Bitterroot Spring RX Fire 2022 Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Tue, 22 Mar 2022 09:17:39</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>See the 'Announcements' and 'News' Tabs for the latest information on planned prescribed burns.</p><p>With the arrival of spring, firefighters across the Bitterroot National Forest are gearing up for their annual prescribed burning operations to reduce hazardous fuels, restore wildlife habitat, and better protect communities from future wildfires.       </p><p>Underburning, a type of prescribed fire treatment, ignites vegetation under the forest canopy or in open grassy meadows and focuses on the consumption of surface fuels.  Frequent, low-intensity fire is essential in improving habitat conditions by regenerating fire-adapted vegetation and encouraging the growth of new forage and food sprouts for wildlife.  </p><p>“This is the time of year when we have the opportunity to be proactive and meet our forest-wide goals of reducing hazardous fuels in key areas near communities,” said David Tingley, Bitterroot National Forest Fuels Fire Management Officer.  “Over the coming weeks, we will be burning on days that maximize safety and minimize smoke impacts to restore healthy forest conditions.”   </p><p>Spring prescribed fire activities normally take place from March to May and burning is highly weather and fuels dependent.  A mosaic pattern of burned and unburned areas will remain after treatments.  </p><p l0="" level1="" style=""></p><p>All total, fire managers plan to burn approximately 3,774 acres this spring.  Smoke may be visible at times from West Fork Highway, East Fork Road, or Highway 93.  Treatment areas include:</p><p>Darby/Sula Ranger District – 2,292 acres are planned:</p> Waddell Units, south of Lake Como  Como/Horse Lick, south of Lost Horse and north of Lake Como- 85 acres complete  Trapper Bunkhouse, SW of Darby between Little Tin Cup & McCoy Creeks - 131 acres complete  Cameron Blue, along East Fork Road near Guide Creek   Teepee Face & Schultz Saddle, east of Sula and north of Springer Memorial    Tolan Ecoburn, east of Sula between Reimel and Tolan CreeksWest Fork Ranger District – 815 acres are planned:Lower West Fork Units, south of Trapper Creek and north of Lloyd Creek  School Point Ecoburn Units, west of Boulder Creek and east of Halford CreekStevensville Ranger District – 667 acres are planned: Upper Larry Bass Units, within the Bass Creek Recreation Area northwest of Stevensville- 620 acres complete Three Saddle Units, Sapphire Mountains east of Stevensville  <p>Prescribed burning operations will only be conducted if conditions are favorable.  Favorable conditions include correct parameters for temperature, wind, fuel moisture, and ventilation for smoke.  When prescription criteria are met, firefighters implement, monitor, and patrol each burn to ensure it meets forest health and public safety goals.   </p><p>All prescribed burns will be implemented in compliance with Montana air quality standards and coordinated with the Montana Department of Environmental Quality to reduce the impacts of smoke to neighbors, cooperators, and surrounding communities.  Smoke may settle in the valley bottoms and drainages overnight, but it is expected to dissipate within a few days.</p><p>For public safety, recreationists are asked to be aware of fire crews and vehicles in these areas.  The public is also asked to avoid traveling in prescribed burn units while crews are present, as well as trails and roads directly adjacent to the units.  Please take caution as roads and trails used as control lines for the burn could be temporarily impacted by low intensity fire and smoke. Maps:<a href="https://usfs.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=7b743b38029e4973b2e6523c976b097b" target="_self">Interactive Planned Prescribed Fire Map</a><a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/maps/8024/" target="_self">Prescribed Burn Unit Maps (PDFs)</a> </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8024/">View Bitterroot Spring RX Fire 2022 Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-114.176</longitude><latitude>46.081</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-114.176,46.081,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Daniel's Ranch RX Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-102.961</longitude><latitude>29.18</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Daniel's Ranch RX Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Wed, 06 Apr 2022 13:06:23</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>On April 6th and 7th, Big Bend National Park staff plan to initiate a 33-acre prescribed burn along the Rio Grande. Fire managers will be using prescribed fire as a natural resource habitat treatment to control exotic giant cane. The project area is located along the River Corridor from Daniel’s Ranch to the Rio Grande Village Nature Trail. During this time, visitors will encounter temporary closures at the Daniel's Ranch area, the Rio Grande Village Nature Trail, and the Rio Grande Village Boat Launch. </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8048/">View Daniel's Ranch RX Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-102.961</longitude><latitude>29.18</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-102.961,29.18,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Presumido Peak Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-111.621</longitude><latitude>31.567</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Presumido Peak Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Tue, 05 Apr 2022 11:47:23</p><p>Incident is 100% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>This fire is 100% contained at 2,591 acres. All resources have been released The human-caused fire started Saturday, March 27, approximately 20 miles north/northwest of Sasabe, within Presumido Peak, in Pima County. </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8036/">View Presumido Peak Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-111.621</longitude><latitude>31.567</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-111.621,31.567,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Kaibab NF South Zone Rx Fire Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-112.217</longitude><latitude>35.186</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Kaibab NF South Zone Rx Fire Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:56:29</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>The Spring 2022 prescribed fire season is upon us. Fire managers will be looking for windows of opportunity to conduct broadcast burns (applying fire across the forest floor) through the month of April and maybe into May, depending on what conditions will allow. Crews are planning to work on the following projects this season: </p>Greenbase Project:  Just north of the City Williams; 3500 acres; Smoke likely noticeable around Williams, Highway 64, and Interstate 40.Reed Project: Just south and northeast of Tusayan; 3300 acres; Overnight smoke generally settles around Forest Road 302, Tusayan, and south toward Red Butte.Blue Stem Project: Remote corner of Tusayan District 15-20 miles east northeast of State Route 64 and Red Butte; Total of approx. 6000 acres; Limited smoke on local roads; minimal impacts to populated areas.  <p>Fire plays a critical role in maintaining a healthy forest and reducing risks of uncharacteristic wildfires that threaten public health and safety.  A healthy forest is a resilient forest where fire occurs on regular basis. </p> <p>Fire managers recognize that smoke can impact residents and visitors. However, because crews have some control over when and how the beneficial fires occur on the landscape, science shows that the amount and duration of smoke from such fires are significantly less than smoke from severe, intense wildfires. The Kaibab National Forest coordinates closely with partners and communities to identify objectives and develop sound and well-informed strategies which include monitoring multiple conditions and taking actions minimize smoke impacts as much as possible. </p> <p>All prescribed fires on the Kaibab National Forest are subject to approval by the Arizona Department of Environmental Quality. The department provides details about its air quality program online at <a href="https://legacy.azdeq.gov/environ/air/smoke/index.html">legacy.azdeq.gov/environ/air/smoke/index.html</a></p> ]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/5922/">View Kaibab NF South Zone Rx Fire Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-112.217</longitude><latitude>35.186</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-112.217,35.186,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Jim Fire Wildfire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-117.512</longitude><latitude>33.691</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Jim Fire Wildfire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Wed, 30 Mar 2022 16:09:25</p><p>Incident is 100% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>On the Trabuco Ranger District in the Holy Jim Canyon area, the Jim Fire began March 2, 2022, at approximately 11:06 a.m. U.S. Forest Service firefighters responded with fire engines, hand crews, and air resources, assisted by the Orange County Fire Authority and Cal Fire Riverside Unit resources. The fire started in a drainage bottom and spread uphill, consuming approximately 500 acres of vegetation. The Jim Fire investigation has concluded. U.S. Forest Service investigators determined the fire was unintentionally ignited during a Forest Service-sponsored wildlife and habitat restoration maintenance project during barrier removal. No structures were destroyed. Three minor injuries to firefighters have been reported. The fire was declared out on Sunday March 27, 2022. 553 acres, 100% contained.</p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7987/">View Jim Fire Wildfire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-117.512</longitude><latitude>33.691</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-117.512,33.691,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>San Juan NF Prescribed Fire Program Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-107.882</longitude><latitude>37.279</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>San Juan NF Prescribed Fire Program Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Thu, 26 Aug 2021 16:45:46</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>The San Juan National Forest Fuels Management Staff are planning pile burns this winter during optimal weather windows, primarily after snowfall.Planned pile burns:Pagosa Springs Ranger District:</p>The Pagosa Ranger District will be conducting pile burns northwest of Pagosa Springs, Colorado on Tuesday, March 29, 2022. There may be smoke in the air, and you may see responding fire vehicles. These pile burns reduce fuels in the area before fire season begins and completes work previously completed by District fire staff.Dolores Ranger District This prescribed burn will be re-scheduled when conditions allow: The Dolores Ranger District Fire and Fuels staff plan to burn slash piles near Joe Moore Reservoir. The project is situated in Montezuma County, in the Millwood/Chicken Creek area of the district, north of Mancos off FSR 559. We plan to burn 300 piles, weather and conditions permitting. Smoke will be visible from Highway 184 and Highway 160, but should stay away from populated areas. Signs will be posted to notify the public of prescribed burning activity near the treatment area.  Ignitions of the piles will not start before 9am and continue past 3pm. There is no need to contact dispatch about smoke seen from this prescribed burn.<p><a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/6288/67827/" target="_self">Here are the 2022 spring prescribed burn plans.</a></p><p>Reintroduction of fire is necessary to improve and restore vegetative conditions. This effort will reduce hazardous ground fuels, lessen the risk of unplanned large-scale wildfire, help restore ecosystems, and improve wildlife habitat. Prescribed fire also reduces the ladder fuels that can carry fire into the canopy, killing mature trees. </p><p style="margin: 6pt 0in; line-height: 13.2096px;">Prescribed fire smoke may affect your health. For information, visit: <a href="https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/cdphe/wood-smoke-and-health">https://www.colorado.gov/pacific/cdphe/wood-smoke-and-health.</a></p><p style="margin-right: -0.25in;">For additional information on planned burns, please contact the San Juan Public Affairs Officer at 970-422-2939.</p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/6288/">View San Juan NF Prescribed Fire Program Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-107.882</longitude><latitude>37.279</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-107.882,37.279,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Jim Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-117.462</longitude><latitude>33.741</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Jim Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Mon, 28 Mar 2022 18:49:47</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p> THREE PHASES OF WILDFIRE RECOVERY<p>  </p> <p>There are three phases of recovery following wildfires on federal lands: </p> <p>-       Fire Suppression Repair </p> <p>-       Emergency Stabilization-Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) </p> <p>-       Long-Term Recovery and Restoration </p> <p>o   Fire Suppression Repair is a series of immediate post-fire actions taken to repair damages and minimize potential soil erosion and impacts resulting from fire suppression activities and usually begins before the fire is contained, and before the demobilization of an Incident Management Team. This work repairs the hand and dozer fire lines, roads, trails, staging areas, safety zones, and drop points used during fire suppression efforts. </p> <p>o   Emergency Stabilization-Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) is a rapid assessment of burned watersheds by a BAER team to identify imminent post-wildfire threats to human life and safety, property, and critical natural or cultural resources on National Forest System lands and take immediate actions to implement emergency stabilization measures before the first post-fire damaging events. Fires result in loss of vegetation, exposure of soil to erosion, and increased water runoff that may lead to flooding, increased sediment, debris flows, and damage to critical natural and cultural resources. BAER actions such as: mulching, seeding, installation of erosion and water run-off control structures, temporary barriers to protect recovering areas, and installation of warning signs may be implemented. BAER work may also replace safety related facilities; remove safety hazards; prevent permanent loss of habitat for threatened and endangered species; prevent the spread of noxious weeds, and protect critical cultural resources. </p> <p>o   Long-Term Recovery and Restoration utilizes non-emergency actions to improve fire-damaged lands that are unlikely to recover naturally and to repair or replace facilities damaged by the fire that are not critical to life and safety. This phase may include restoring burned habitat, reforestation, other planting or seeding, monitoring fire effects, replacing burned fences, interpreting cultural sites, treating noxious weed infestations, and installing interpretive signs. </p> <p style="background:white; margin-bottom:7.5pt; margin-left:0in; margin-right:0in; margin-top:0in;"> BAER SAFETY MESSAGE: Everyone near and downstream from the burned areas should remain alert and stay updated on weather conditions that may result in heavy rains over the burn scars. Flash flooding may occur quickly during heavy rain events be prepared to take action. Current weather and emergency notifications can be found at the National Weather Service website: <a href="http://www.weather.gov/sgx/">www.weather.gov/sgx/</a>. </p></p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8000/">View Jim Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-117.462</longitude><latitude>33.741</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-117.462,33.741,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Cleveland RX Burning 2022 Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-116.801</longitude><latitude>33.3</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Cleveland RX Burning 2022 Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Mon, 28 Mar 2022 17:24:27</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>Each year the Cleveland National Forest conducts prescribed burns from January to May 2022, if weather and fuel moisture conditions permit. The objectives of the projects are to reduce the risk of catastrophic wildfire to people and communities, create conditions which offer a safer and more effective wildfire response, foster more resilient ecosystems, and minimize the effects of large wildfires on the landscape. In fiscal year 2022, the Forest's target for fuels reduction is 3,500 acres. 2,000 acres of planned prescribed fire, and 1,500 acres of mechanical treatments which is a combination of mastication, cut and pile with chainsaws.When implementing these projects, fire managers follow a burn plan that outlines the “prescription” or environmental conditions such as temperature, wind, fuel moisture, ventilation and relative humidity that need to be present before the project begins. When the criteria are met, crews implement, monitor, and patrol each burn to ensure it meets the goals and objectives outlined by managers. The prescribed fire program will continue through the winter and spring months as permitted by weather and other environmental factors.Trabuco Ranger District: Plans between 400 and 700 acres around the communities of Rancho Capistrano, Long Canyon, Silverado, El Cariso, Temescal and Corona. Heavy smoke may be visible from surrounding communities.Palomar Ranger District: Plans between 500 and 600 acres in 2022, mainly in the areas of Fry Creek/ Palomar Mountain, on the Palomar Divide, Morgan Hill, and Indian Flats.Descanso Ranger District: Plans between 300 and 700 acres. Piles will be burned within a fuel break around communities. Piles consist of cut and piled chaparral and coastal sage scrub. The piles will be burned in blocks as weather and conditions permit.  Prescribed pile burns on Mount Laguna will be conducted in several different areas, Wooded Hill, Thing Valley, Kitchen creek rd. The fuels consist of cut and piled chaparral in some units and timber litter in others. Proposed broadcast burns in the areas of Wooded Hill are also planned. The burns will assist in community protection as well as limiting the severity of a wildfire during the summer months. These burns are being conducted to promote forest health. The prescribed areas will be burned in blocks as weather and conditions permit. Some drifting smoke may be visible during the period of burning along Sunrise Highway, Buckman Springs Road, Interstate 8, and within the community of Lake Morena.Residents in the area should call their local district office for more information on burn projects.</p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7317/">View Cleveland RX Burning 2022 Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-116.801</longitude><latitude>33.3</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-116.801,33.3,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>2022 Humboldt-Toiyabe Prescribed Fire Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-119.769</longitude><latitude>39.524</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>2022 Humboldt-Toiyabe Prescribed Fire Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Wed, 23 Feb 2022 12:01:04</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p> </p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"> </p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"><a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/7310/67659/" target="_blank">Planned Projects</a> | <a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/7310/67663/" target="_self">Current Projects</a> | <a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/photographs/7310/" target="_blank">Current Photos</a></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;">As part of Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest’s hazardous fuels reduction efforts, crews will conduct prescribed fire across pre-planned locations across the forest as weather and fuel conditions permit. Prescribed fire is a proactive tool used to achieve a number of purposes, including the reduction of hazardous fuels, which decreases the threat of high intensity, high-severity wildfires. It also reduces the risk of insect and disease outbreak, recycles nutrients that increase soil productivity and improves wildlife habitat. The actual days of ignition for prescribed burning will depend on several factors including appropriate humidity levels, wind speed and direction, temperature, and fuel moisture. Burns only occur on days when weather conditions exist for good smoke dispersal. </p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"> Residents and visitors are asked to avoid areas where prescribed burns are being conducted. Smoke may be visible, but these fires are all carefully monitored and local fire departments  are aware of prescribed fire activity. Get updates on prescribed burns on the Forest's Facebook and Twitter pages: Humboldt-Toiyabe NF Facebook:<a href="https://www.facebook.com/HumboldtToiyabeNF/">https://www.facebook.com/HumboldtToiyabeNF/</a> Humboldt-Toiyabe Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/HumboldtToiyabe">https://twitter.com/HumboldtToiyabe</a> For a list of prescribed fire projects currently planned for 2022 (to be implemented as local weather and fuel conditions allow), please go to the <a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/7310/67659/" target="_self">Planned Project List</a>. To learn more about the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest's prescribed fire program, please visit: <a class="oajrlxb2 g5ia77u1 qu0x051f esr5mh6w e9989ue4 r7d6kgcz rq0escxv nhd2j8a9 nc684nl6 p7hjln8o kvgmc6g5 cxmmr5t8 oygrvhab hcukyx3x jb3vyjys rz4wbd8a qt6c0cv9 a8nywdso i1ao9s8h esuyzwwr f1sip0of lzcic4wl gpro0wi8 py34i1dx" href="https://bit.ly/HTNFPrescribedFire?fbclid=IwAR2CmDibL2cqiHsa3kRkywuXUqthzkwlw81hSgwQ82pmxl6vHPEHVCZMavk" rel="nofollow noopener" role="link" style="cursor: pointer; text-decoration-line: none; outline: none; list-style: none; border-width: 0px; border-style: initial; border-color: initial; padding: 0px; margin: 0px; touch-action: manipulation; background-color: transparent; text-align: inherit; display: inline; -webkit-tap-highlight-color: transparent; box-sizing: border-box;" tabindex="0" target="_blank">https://bit.ly/HTNFPrescribedFire</a>.An ArcGIS StoryMap that explains how prescribe fire is good for the National Forest System land can be viewed at  <a href="https://bit.ly/PrescribedFireStoryMap" style="text-align: -webkit-center; color: rgb(0, 0, 153); text-decoration-line: none;">https://bit.ly/PrescribedFireStoryMap</a>.</p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"> </p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"> </p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"></p><p style="margin: 0in 0in 8pt;"> </p> ]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7310/">View 2022 Humboldt-Toiyabe Prescribed Fire Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-119.769</longitude><latitude>39.524</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-119.769,39.524,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Indiana Dunes NP Spring 2022 Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-87.19</longitude><latitude>41.617</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Indiana Dunes NP Spring 2022 Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Tue, 15 Mar 2022 14:55:13</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p> Indiana Dunes National Park is planning 6 prescribed fires for the Spring of 2022. </p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/8001/">View Indiana Dunes NP Spring 2022 Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-87.19</longitude><latitude>41.617</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-87.19,41.617,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Hoosier National Forest Prescribed Fire  Prescribed Fire</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-86.468</longitude><latitude>38.556</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Hoosier National Forest Prescribed Fire  Prescribed Fire Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Tue, 01 Mar 2022 07:05:16</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 0px 5pt; padding: 0px; color: rgb(51, 51, 51); text-transform: none; line-height: 1.4em; text-indent: 0px; letter-spacing: normal; font-family: Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 0.9em; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400; word-spacing: 0px; white-space: normal; max-width: 520px; orphans: 2; widows: 2; background-color: rgb(255, 253, 238); overflow-wrap: break-word; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">Bedford, Indiana. October 22, 2021 — The U.S. Forest Service plans to conduct seasonal prescribed burning to maintain, restore or improve early successional habitat, maintain wetlands, restore and maintain unique barren ecosystems, regenerate oak and hickory tree species and improve soil health by naturally returning nutrients to the soil.  Historical data shows that throughout history natural occurring fire played a vital and necessary role in sustaining the eastern deciduous forest ecosystem. Scientific research supports the use of prescribed burning to reintroduce low intensity fire to its natural role within the ecosystem. Prescribed burning also reduces fuel loading, thereby lowering the risk of catastrophic wildfire.  </p><p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 0px 5pt; padding: 0px; color: rgb(51, 51, 51); text-transform: none; line-height: 1.4em; text-indent: 0px; letter-spacing: normal; font-family: Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 0.9em; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400; word-spacing: 0px; white-space: normal; max-width: 520px; orphans: 2; widows: 2; background-color: rgb(255, 253, 238); overflow-wrap: break-word; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">Approximately 4,500 - 5,000 acres are planned to receive treatment with prescribed fire in the fall of 2021 on National Forest System lands in the following counties:  Brown, Crawford, Jackson, Martin, Monroe, Lawrence, and Perry. </p><p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 0px 5pt; padding: 0px; color: rgb(51, 51, 51); text-transform: none; line-height: 1.4em; text-indent: 0px; letter-spacing: normal; font-family: Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 0.9em; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400; word-spacing: 0px; white-space: normal; max-width: 520px; orphans: 2; widows: 2; background-color: rgb(255, 253, 238); overflow-wrap: break-word; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">U.S. Forest Service fire managers utilize National Weather Service data to determine the best days to burn to achieve desired effects and to maximize safety. Many specific conditions must be met for a burn to occur, including fuel moisture, wind speed and direction, and relative humidity, among other factors. Decisions are generally made the day of the burn once parameters have been measured or forecasted. Therefore, advance specific notification for a particular burn can be difficult. Forest staff notifies the public in the immediate area of the prescribed burn. The public is advised to check the forest’s social media accounts for announcements of burns on <a href="http://www.facebook.com/HoosierNF/" style="color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/HoosierNF" style="color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;">Twitter</a>.  Maps and additional details of the burn areas will be available through <a href="https://inciweb.nwcg.gov/" style="color: rgb(0, 0, 153); font-weight: bold; text-decoration: none;">InciWeb</a>. .</p><p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 0px 5pt; padding: 0px; color: rgb(51, 51, 51); text-transform: none; line-height: 1.4em; text-indent: 0px; letter-spacing: normal; font-family: Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 0.9em; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400; word-spacing: 0px; white-space: normal; max-width: 520px; orphans: 2; widows: 2; background-color: rgb(255, 253, 238); overflow-wrap: break-word; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">All designated burn areas will not be accessible to the public on the day of the burn and for some time after the burn until the area is considered safe. If any hazards are identified within the burn area, the area may be inaccessible for several days for public safety. Burning may affect access to hunting areas. For your safety, please contact the Indiana Interagency Coordination Center dispatch (812-547-9262) if you plan to hunt or camp in or near prescribed burn areas.</p><p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 0px 5pt; padding: 0px; color: rgb(51, 51, 51); text-transform: none; line-height: 1.4em; text-indent: 0px; letter-spacing: normal; font-family: Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 0.9em; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400; word-spacing: 0px; white-space: normal; max-width: 520px; orphans: 2; widows: 2; background-color: rgb(255, 253, 238); overflow-wrap: break-word; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">An unfortunate side effect of prescribed burning is smoke. Fire managers burn only under atmospheric conditions specified in a burn plan and rely on scientific data to choose days in which the impacts of smoke are minimized. Smoke plumes from a prescribed fire usually rise high into the air where the smoke dissipates.  When smoke is present, motorists should reduce speeds and turn on headlights.</p><p style="margin: 0.5em 0px 0px 5pt; padding: 0px; color: rgb(51, 51, 51); text-transform: none; line-height: 1.4em; text-indent: 0px; letter-spacing: normal; font-family: Verdana, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 0.9em; font-style: normal; font-weight: 400; word-spacing: 0px; white-space: normal; max-width: 520px; orphans: 2; widows: 2; background-color: rgb(255, 253, 238); overflow-wrap: break-word; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">All burns are implemented under carefully planned prescriptions and protocols to mitigate the risk of an escaped fire and smoke exposure to communities. All planned activities have been carefully coordinated with county emergency management agencies. Forest neighbors who wish to be notified of a specific date of a burn, or those who wish to report medical conditions that could be affected by smoke, may contact the Indiana Interagency Coordination Center Dispatcher at 812-547-9262.</p>]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7887/">View Hoosier National Forest Prescribed Fire  Prescribed Fire web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-86.468</longitude><latitude>38.556</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-86.468,38.556,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>Caldor Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-120.333</longitude><latitude>38.753</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>Caldor Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Wed, 02 Feb 2022 15:24:01</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p>SPECIAL SAFETY NOTE: Everyone near and downstream from the burned areas should remain alert and stay updated on weather conditions that may result in heavy rains and increased water runoff. Flash flooding may occur quickly during heavy rain events-be prepared to take action. Current weather and emergency notifications can be found at the National Weather Service website: <a href="http://www.weather.gov/sto/" style="font-size: 16px; box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">www.weather.gov/sto/</a>. </p><p style="box-sizing: border-box; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> Caldor Post-Fire BAER—Preparing for Rain Events </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> POST-FIRE WATERSHED CONDITIONS—KEY MESSAGES </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> While many wildfires cause minimal damage to the land and pose few threats to the land or people downstream, some fires cause damage that requires special efforts to prevent problems afterwards. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> Thunderstorms and winter rain events in the Sierra Nevada mountains can result in high water runoff and flooding. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> Wildfire increases the potential for flooding, post-fire soil erosion and debris flows that could impact campgrounds, fishing areas, homes, structures, roads, and other infrastructure within, adjacent to, and downstream from the burned areas. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> Post-fire, watershed conditions will naturally receive and transport water and sediment differently than during pre-fire conditions. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> The public and communities adjacent to and downstream from the wildfire areas should expect increased flooding and debris transport during less than average rain events. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> SAFETY CONCERNS CONTINUE AFTER THE FIRE IS OUT </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> The potential for increased water runoff and debris flows are not just a one-year concern. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> We need to recognize the threat potential of flash floods and debris flows may exist for the next several years, depending on the intensity of these storms. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> For life and safety concerns, burned area national forest closures may need to be implemented prior to forecast rain events until the burned area fully recovers. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> Residents and visitors should remain alert to weather events and plan ahead when travelling along roads within and downstream from the burned areas of the Caldor Fire. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> ASSESSING CALDOR BURNED WATERSHEDS RESPONSE </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> A Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team has been working with the Eldorado National Forest and Lake Tahoe Basin Management Unit, to assess the condition of the watersheds on National Forest System (NFS) land burned in the Caldor Fire. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> The BAER assessment team identifies potential emergency threats to critical BAER values, and recommends emergency stabilization response actions that are implemented on federal land to reduce potential post-fire threats. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> BAER critical values that may be considered at-risk on federal lands are: </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> §  Human life and safety. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> §  Property such as buildings, water systems and infrastructure, utility systems, road and trail prisms. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> §  Critical natural resources such as water, soil productivity and hydrologic function, areas where invasive species or noxious weeds may impact native or naturalized communities and may include critical habitat or suitable occupied habitat for federally listed threatened or endangered species. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> §  Critical cultural and heritage resources such as pre-historic and historic properties and sites. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> ASSISTANCE FOR PRIVATE LAND AND HOMEOWNERS ADJACENT TO AND DOWNSTREAM FROM BURNED AREAS </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> For values and resources potentially impacted off federal lands, one of the most effective BAER strategies is interagency coordination with local cooperators who assist affected businesses, homes, and landowners with preparing for rain events.  </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> While multi-agency efforts are being taken to reduce the risks to life and safety adjacent to and downstream from the burned areas, nearby residents should develop individual plans to protect themselves and their property.  </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> The Forest Service and Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) work together and coordinate with other federal, state and local agencies, and counties that assist private landowners in preparing for increased run-off and potential flooding impacts. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> NRCS and local sponsors prepare damage survey reports for eligible sites on private lands adjacent to and downstream from affected areas.  NRCS uses these reports, along with the Forest Service BAER team’s assessment report, to develop emergency measures to reduce the impacts from potential increased water and debris flows, and assist local sponsors to implement recommended emergency measures through its Emergency Watershed Protection (EWP) Program: (<a href="http://www.nrcs.usda.gov/Internet/FSE_DOCUMENTS/stelprdb1045263.pdf" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">www.nrcs.usda.gov/Internet/FSE_DOCUMENTS/stelprdb1045263.pdf</a>). </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> All EWP Program–Recovery projects begin with a local sponsor or legal subdivision of state or tribal government. Eligible sponsors include cities, counties, towns, conservation districts, or any federally-recognized Native American tribe or tribal organization. Interested public and private landowners can apply for EWP Program–Recovery assistance through one of those sponsors. For more information on NRCS Disaster Assistance Programs: <a href="https://www.nrcs.usda.gov/wps/portal/nrcs/detail/ca/newsroom/features/?cid=nrcseprd1287608" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">NRCS CA Post-Fire Disaster Assistance</a>. </p> <p style="box-sizing: border-box; font-size: 16px; margin-bottom: 10px; margin-top: 0px;"> The following state and local county offices of emergency management promote preparedness through its emergency services programs to assist the public to prepare for, respond appropriately to, and quickly recover from natural emergencies that may impact county residents and visitors: </p>   <a href="https://ucanr.edu/sites/postfire/Landowners_Guide_to_Fire/Post_Fire_Land_Evaluation_-_Management/Damage_Assessment/" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">Recovering from Wildfire-Damage Assessments</a>   <a href="https://acwi.gov/swrr/p&p_library/May_2018/11_coe_swrr_wret_presentation_may_2018.pdf" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">CA WERT Program-Post-Fire Watershed Recovery</a>     <a href="https://www.edcgov.us/emergencyservices" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">El Dorado County Emergency Services</a>   <a href="https://www.edcgov.us/Government/building/Pages/Caldor-Fire.aspx" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">El Dorado County – Caldor Fire Recovery Information</a>     <a href="https://www.amadorgov.org/departments/office-of-emergency-services" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">Amador County Office of Emergency Services</a>   <a href="https://www.amadorgov.org/departments/transportation-and-public-works" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">Amador County Transportation & Public Works</a>     <a href="http://www.alpinecountyca.gov/169/Public-Works" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">Alpine County Public Works</a>   <a href="https://alpinecountyca.gov/list.aspx" style="box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">Alpine County Emergency Alerts</a>   Homes or businesses that could be impacted by flooding from federal land that resulted from wildfires may be eligible for flood insurance coverage from the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP).  Information about NFIP is available through FEMA at <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fema.gov%2Fnational-flood-insurance-program&data=02%7C01%7C%7C7e934df02de14676c7c008d817b7d2b1%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637285425563923102&sdata=uM%2BJypJXwC2fZddq7FNlbYo8wjek81H%2BVmulbcXjvpw%3D&reserved=0" style="font-size: 16px; box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">www.fema.gov/national-flood-insurance-program</a>, or <a href="https://www.floodsmart.gov/wildfires" style="font-size: 16px; box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">FEMA Wildfire Increases Flood Risk</a>. Other flood preparedness information is available at <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ready.gov%2Ffloods&data=02%7C01%7C%7C7e934df02de14676c7c008d817b7d2b1%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637285425563933053&sdata=gsGAcssqoDygW4oUmUuwac4M7Vm8sCP3twaCZ4nOaw0%3D&reserved=0" style="font-size: 16px; box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">www.ready.gov/floods</a> and <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.floodsmart.gov%2F&data=02%7C01%7C%7C7e934df02de14676c7c008d817b7d2b1%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637285425563933053&sdata=0Abdh7HuaoufTqA%2Fh0quLePU23AdI1DpSGWTqNIDv1Y%3D&reserved=0" style="font-size: 16px; box-sizing: border-box; color: rgb(37, 102, 181); text-decoration-line: none;">www.floodsmart.gov/</a>.]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7842/">View Caldor Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-120.333</longitude><latitude>38.753</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-120.333,38.753,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><Folder class="parent_folder"><name>River Complex Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response</name><LookAt><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt><longitude>-123.207</longitude><latitude>41.222</latitude></LookAt><Placemark><name>River Complex Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response Information</name><description><p><strong>Last updated:</strong> Tue, 01 Feb 2022 12:52:20</p><p>Incident is 0% contained.</p><![CDATA[<p align="center" style="background:#FEFCA6; margin:0in; text-align:center;"> SPECIAL SAFETY NOTE: Everyone near and downstream from the burned areas should remain alert and stay updated on weather conditions that may result in heavy rains, increased water runoff. Flash flooding and landslides may occur quickly during heavy rain events-be prepared to take action – especially at these locations such as Walker, Grider, Horse Creek, Scott River, and others. Current weather and emergency notifications can be found at the National Weather Service websites: <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwwwweather.gov%2Feka%2F&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226373892%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=re6yVpoGaT2xu4dhyTR1zFGo9I7A8uY17xhFYwTyw%2BA%3D&reserved=0">wwwweather.gov/eka/</a> and <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.weather.gov%2Fsto%2F&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226383845%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=aW6z4La9IlofoN8OwL9Jhn32udg40L1xEuqgy%2BjOF4k%3D&reserved=0">www.weather.gov/sto/</a>.</p> <p align="center"style="text-align:center;"> Post-Fire BAER—Preparing for Rain Events</p> <p>POST-FIRE WATERSHED CONDITIONS—KEY MESSAGES</p> <p>While many wildfires cause minimal damage to the land and pose few threats to the land or people downstream, some fires cause damage that requires special efforts to prevent problems afterwards.</p> <p>Thunderstorms and winter rain events in the Sierra Nevada, Cascade and Klamath mountains can result in high water runoff and flooding.</p> <p>Wildfire increases the potential for flooding, post-fire soil erosion and debris flows that could impact campgrounds, fishing areas, homes, structures, roads, and other infrastructure within, adjacent to, and downstream from the burned areas.</p> <p>Post-fire, watershed conditions will naturally receive and transport water and sediment differently than during pre-fire conditions.</p> <p>The public and communities adjacent to and downstream from the wildfire areas should expect increased flooding and debris transport during less than average rain events.</p> <p>SAFETY CONCERNS CONTINUE AFTER THE FIRE IS OUT</p> <p>The potential for increased water runoff and debris flows are not just a one-year concern.</p> <p>We need to recognize the threat potential of flash floods and debris flows may exist for the next several years, depending on the intensity of these storms.</p> <p>For life and safety concerns, burned area national forest closures may need to be implemented prior to forecast rain events until the burned area fully recovers.</p> <p>Residents and visitors should remain alert to weather events and plan ahead when travelling along roads within and downstream from the burned areas of the River Complex and McCash fires.</p> <p>ASSESSING MCCASH FIRE & RIVER COMPLEX BURNED WATERSHEDS RESPONSE</p> <p>A Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) team has been working with the Shasta-Trinity, Klamath and Six Rivers National Forests, to assess the condition of the watersheds on National Forest System (NFS) land burned in the River Complex and McCash fires.</p> <p>The BAER assessment team identifies potential emergency threats to critical BAER values, and recommends emergency stabilization response actions that are implemented on federal land to reduce potential post-fire threats.</p> <p>BAER critical values that may be considered at-risk on federal lands are: </p>  §  Human life and safety. </p>  §  Property such as buildings, water systems and infrastructure, utility systems, road and trail prisms. </p>  §  Critical natural resources such as water, soil productivity and hydrologic function, areas where invasive species or noxious weeds may impact native or naturalized communities and may include critical habitat or suitable occupied habitat for federally listed threatened or endangered species. </p>  §  Critical cultural and heritage resources such as pre-historic and historic properties and sites.</p> <p>ASSISTANCE FOR PRIVATE LAND AND HOMEOWNERS ADJACENT TO AND DOWNSTREAM FROM BURNED AREAS</p> <p>For values and resources potentially impacted off federal lands, one of the most effective BAER strategies is interagency coordination with local cooperators who assist affected businesses, homes, and landowners with preparing for rain events. </p> <p>While multi-agency efforts are being taken to reduce the risks to life and safety adjacent to and downstream from the burned areas, nearby residents should develop individual plans to protect themselves and their property. </p> <p>The Forest Service and Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) work together and coordinate with other federal, state and local agencies, and counties that assist private landowners in preparing for increased run-off and potential flooding impacts. </p> <p style="background:white; margin-bottom:12.0pt;"> NRCS and local sponsors prepare damage survey reports for eligible sites on private lands adjacent to and downstream from affected areas.  NRCS uses these reports, along with the Forest Service BAER team’s assessment report, to develop emergency measures to reduce the impacts from potential increased water and debris flows, and assist local sponsors to implement recommended emergency measures through its Emergency Watershed Protection (EWP) Program: (<a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nrcs.usda.gov%2FInternet%2FFSE_DOCUMENTS%2Fstelprdb1045263.pdf&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226383845%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=uLewexELNIddS1F%2FVQJ6JjM4YIRycuVUrHTkbjFzG0w%3D&reserved=0">www.nrcs.usda.gov/Internet/FSE_DOCUMENTS/stelprdb1045263.pdf</a>). </p> <p style="background:white; margin-bottom:12.0pt;"> All EWP Program–Recovery projects begin with a local sponsor or legal subdivision of state or tribal government. Eligible sponsors include cities, counties, towns, conservation districts, or any federally-recognized Native American tribe or tribal organization. Interested public and private landowners can apply for EWP Program–Recovery assistance through one of those sponsors. For more information on NRCS Disaster Assistance Programs: <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nrcs.usda.gov%2Fwps%2Fportal%2Fnrcs%2Fdetail%2Fca%2Fnewsroom%2Ffeatures%2F%3Fcid%3Dnrcseprd1287608&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226393803%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=18PRU7CqMRCEBR13lbbOxwGIW70WWp5OB4M1ExEzsjY%3D&reserved=0">NRCS CA Post-Fire Disaster Assistance</a>. </p> <p>The following state and local county offices of emergency management promote preparedness through its emergency services programs to assist the public to prepare for, respond appropriately to, and quickly recover from natural emergencies that may impact county residents and visitors:</p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fucanr.edu%2Fsites%2Fpostfire%2FLandowners_Guide_to_Fire%2FPost_Fire_Land_Evaluation_-_Management%2FDamage_Assessment%2F&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226393803%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=p5y6jnn8mz7uPPio6OMOJrfCl49mV%2B2Ip5fuXJTHLH4%3D&reserved=0">Recovering from Wildfire-Damage Assessments</a></p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.trinitycounty.org%2FOES&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226393803%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=jzG2LhyM4KN0aohNjzgj1%2FCzN0G9BLu2tvM4%2FUvy1Cs%3D&reserved=0">Trinity County Office of Emergency Services</a> </p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.trinitycounty.org%2FTrinity-County-Water-Resources&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226403757%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=ti%2Bm1u%2B4fWPEtyWN1psYA%2BKuXVj8uO9J7Z8BOtsJc5A%3D&reserved=0">Trinity County Water Resources</a> </p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.trinitycounty.org%2FTransportation&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226403757%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=8TJgKwF1A4IXQeczC%2B7R7rnJRt6X6L3p%2FI1eqPLcVg8%3D&reserved=0">Trinity County Department of Transportation</a></p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.co.siskiyou.ca.us%2Femergencyservices&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226413718%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=zRyhtJ3jAEgsTgXRfOlRogm56xrp6VrXkaIZ7Kp9v5Q%3D&reserved=0">Siskiyou County Emergency Services</a> </p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.co.siskiyou.ca.us%2Fpublichealth%2Fpage%2Femergency-preparedness&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226413718%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=f%2FcHclS43D%2BQpf882WUsFNJGsqm02tAZGPu6GkBx%2BvY%3D&reserved=0">Siskiyou County Emergency Preparedness</a> </p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.co.siskiyou.ca.us%2Ffloodcontrol%2Fpage%2Fflood-control-and-water-conservation-district&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226423670%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=c%2BT%2Bcxq3PI7wcLfHQmQyV41HFXd%2FQ4f2jmw8Kdr8cHY%3D&reserved=0">Siskiyou County Flood Control</a> </p> <p>·       <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.co.siskiyou.ca.us%2Fpublicworks&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226423670%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=u3HJYkzSCWFs5R54CW0oS4%2BmcTifbQK4BJ781uDgl8w%3D&reserved=0">Siskiyou County Public Works</a> </p> Homes or businesses that could be impacted by flooding from federal land that resulted from wildfires may be eligible for flood insurance coverage from the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP).  Information about NFIP is available through FEMA at <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.fema.gov%2Fnational-flood-insurance-program&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226423670%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=Hsa5BkHT7VtG8I3%2FirSUkEOM9lbZ1AraNWhuvKgEJcM%3D&reserved=0">www.fema.gov/national-flood-insurance-program</a>, or <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.floodsmart.gov%2Fwildfires&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226433627%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=bsecgawWR4tawPw6v6j9Ii4e1gwQW1LOATAz%2FwyplVQ%3D&reserved=0">FEMA Wildfire Increases Flood Risk</a>. Other flood preparedness information is available at <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ready.gov%2Ffloods&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226433627%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=wbPTKzOGApBeABMdUusgjAKHpjvvDjZPE9dp%2BxlNIUU%3D&reserved=0">www.ready.gov/floods</a> at <a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.floodsmart.gov%2F&data=04%7C01%7C%7C370eb938b5064582c65e08d995961cb5%7Ced5b36e701ee4ebc867ee03cfa0d4697%7C0%7C0%7C637705294226443587%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C1000&sdata=f%2BWwJzjLXb6GAAQ2q%2FqGqegA%2BIzQZ7VZvUw8uR3YLzc%3D&reserved=0">www.floodsmart.gov/</a>.]]><p><a href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/7868/">View River Complex Post-Fire BAER Burned Area Emergency Response web site</a></p><p><strong>NOTE: </strong> All fire perimeters and points are approximations.</p></description><LookAt><longitude>-123.207</longitude><latitude>41.222</latitude><range>10000</range><tilt>40</tilt></LookAt><styleUrl>#m_ylw-pushpin_copy1</styleUrl><Point><coordinates>-123.207,41.222,0</coordinates></Point></Placemark></Folder><ScreenOverlay><Icon><href>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/images/banners/google.png</href></Icon><name>InciWeb Banner</name><overlayXY x="0" y="1" xunits="fraction" yunits="fraction"/><screenXY x="0" y="1" xunits="fraction" yunits="fraction"/><rotationXY x="0" y="0" xunits="fraction" yunits="fraction"/><size x="0" y="0" xunits="fraction" yunits="fraction"/></ScreenOverlay></Document></kml>